João Palmeiro

Hic Sunt Bitaites • palmeiro.link/new

Lisbon, PT ☑ jm.palmeiro@campus.fct.unl.pt ☐ t.me/joaopalmeiro ☒ joaompalmeiro

Hi! I'm João and I'm working as a Data Visualization Engineer at Feedzai. As part of the Research Department, we develop new charts and tools to support data scientists and fraud analysts. Each day is a mix of User Experience, Data Visualization, and Python/Front-End Programming. Also, I enjoy working on (personal) open-source projects, exploring/visualizing different datasets, and eating (I really like food).

Experience

Data Visualization Engineer, Feedzai

Full-time • Since Mar 2021

BLOG POST

Analyzing Data Drift: How We Designed Visualizations to Support Feature Investigation • palmeiro.link/fi-blog

PAPER

Data+Shift: Supporting visual investigation of data distribution shifts by data scientists • palmeiro.link/ds-paper • palmeiro.link/ds-video • palmeiro.link/ds-slides

BLOG POST Styling Altair Charts with the feedzai-altair-theme • palmeiro.link/alt-blog

Research Intern, Feedzai

Internship • Nov 2019 - Feb 2021

MSc THESIS Meval: A Visual Machine Learning Model Evaluation Tool for Financial Crime Detection • palmeiro.link/thesis

Engineering Intern, Feedzai

Summer internship • Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

BLOG POST Plotting the first point of the Feedzai Charting Library. • palmeiro.link/si-blog

Assistant Consultant, everis (NTT DATA)

Summer internship • Jul 2018 - Sep 2018

TECH STACK Drupal and Web Development • palmeiro.link/si-stack

Education

Course (200h), User Experience & User Interface Design

Grade: 19/20 • EDIT. • Mar 2022 - Jul 2022

MSc, Analysis and Engineering of Big Data

Grade: 17/20 • FCT NOVA • Sep 2018 - Jan 2021

Minor, History and Philosophy of Science

Grade: 18/20 • FCUL • Sep 2018 - Jun 2019

BSc, Information Systems and Computer Engineering

Grade: 13/20 • IST • Sep 2013 - Jul 2018

Workshop (12h), UX Writing Foundations

EDIT. • May 2022 - Jun 2022

Workshop (12h), Web Copywriting

EDIT. • Mar 2022

New Year's Course (25h), Introduction to Data Journalism

Grade: 20/20 • NOVA FCSH • Jan 2020

See more at palmeiro.link

Вē

DEV

 \otimes

\$

 \bigcirc



My writings • /writings
My static charts • /charts
My read books • /books